<resources>
    <string name="app_name">Alliance Ritual Marshal</string>

    <!-- Before Casting Strings -->

    <string name="begin_casting"><b>Get Ritual Ready:</b>
        \nUpon arrival, the ritual marshal will take the following steps, with which the players involved should cooperate:
        \n• Ritual marshal identifies the primary caster and any additional casters who will assist in the ritual;
        \n• Ritual marshal reviews the casters’ player cards to note how many levels of the appropriate school of Formal Magic they possess. Note that a Ritual Caster may choose to not use all of their Ritual Levels when casting if they so desire;
        \n• Ritual marshal reads the first ritual scroll thoroughly, asking relevant questions. For example, if the scroll has the ability to cast a more powerful form of the ritual, the marshal should ask the player what level of the ritual the caster is attempting;
        \n• Ritual marshal confirms that all the required components and recipients are present within a valid Circle of Power;
        \n• Ritual marshal calculates and informs the players of the Difficulty Rating of the ritual;
        \n• Ritual marshal calculates and informs the players of the chance of success of the ritual as follows: The Success Number used for the ritual roll is ten plus the primary caster’s Formal Magic levels minus the ritual’s Difficulty Rating. If using secondary casters to aid in the ritual, add one to the number of caster formal levels for each valid secondary caster participating;
        \n• Ritual marshal repeats this process for each ritual the players intend to conduct;
        \n• Ritual marshal informs the players they may begin the first ritual;
        \n• The caster casts the Circle of Power spell if a permanent Circle of Power is not being used.</string>

    <!-- During Casting Strings -->

    <string name="during_casting"><b>Process of Ritual Casting:</b>
        \nAfter the caster states “Begin ritual casting,” the following steps must occur before the ritual is deemed complete:
        \n1. The ritual marshal calls a Hold;
        \n2. If the recipient of the ritual is an individual, the ritual marshal will ask the recipient, “A ritual is being cast on you. Do you accept it?” (Note that a player must accept the rituals Banish to Other Plane, Divestiture, and Obliteration.) If the player says “no,” the ritual marshal must follow the rules set forth below under the heading “Unwilling Targets”;
        \n3. The ritual marshal makes sure that everyone in the Circle of Power is awake out-of-game.
        \n4. The ritual marshal assures that the properly begin;
        \n5. If the ritual has not yet failed or automatically backlashed, the ritual marshal tells everyone in the Circle of Power, “There is magic all around you”;
        \n6. The ritual marshal calls “Lay on”;
        \n7. The ritual marshal rolls the ten-sided die once where the caster can observe the die roll. As the die roll takes place before the ritual completes, the caster has in-game knowledge of whether something is not going well with the casting and may use Terminate Casting to abort the ritual based on the die roll;
        \n8. The ritual marshal determines if the ritual fails for any reason other than the die roll;
        \n9. The ritual marshal waits the duration of the ritual casting, in case a condition occurs that would cause an automatic backlash;
        \n10. Assuming the ritual has not automatically backlashed, the ritual marshal announces either “You have successfully completed the ritual” (if the ritual succeeded) or “Something has gone dreadfully wrong” (if it does not).
        \nThe Ritual has now ended.
        \n\n<b>Determine Success or Failure:</b>
        \nAssuming no automatic failure or backlash occurs, the success or failure of the ritual is determined using a ten-sided die as follows:
        \n• If the number is less than or equal to the Success Number and is not “0,” then the ritual succeeds.
        \n• If the number is greater than the Success Number or is “0,” then the ritual marshal rolls a second ten-sided die. Any result but a “0” on the second die roll indicates a flaw. A “0” on the second die roll indicates a backlash, which requires the ritual marshal to roll a third ten-sided die and look on the backlash table on the ritual scroll to determine the form of the back-lash.
        \nA successful ritual follows the procedure set forth in “Success,” below. A ritual that fails or backlashes follows the procedure set forth in “Failure,” below.
        \nSuccess: The ritual marshal either awards the successful caster a temporary tag for the ritual conducted or makes sure the ritual effect is carried out by informing the Plot Committee or by personally overseeing the ritual’s effect. A temporary tag allows the ritual marshal to write down the rituals conducted and indicate that a permanent tag for the ritual should be awarded at the end of the event or at the beginning of the next event that the recipient of the ritual attends.
        \nThe temporary tag should indicate the ritual’s name, duration, recipient, effect of the ritual, and any other pertinent information. The temporary tag should be signed by the ritual marshal. If any skills or spells were placed within the recipient, the tags for those skills and spells should be attached to the temporary tag. Recipients should make sure the temporary tag has accurate information and is signed by the proper staff member(s).
        \nPlease note that the Plot Committee reserves the right to assign plot effects that may not be set forth in the ritual scroll. When this occurs, the Plot Committee will likely designate such plot effects effective only in the local chapter.
        \nFailure or Backlash: If the ritual fails or backlashes, a ritual marshal will determine the effect, if any, of the failure or backlash based on the scroll’s charts. Any lasting effects will be written on the player cards of any individuals affected.
        \nCasters are expected to role-play and resolve their flaws and backlashes without complaint for the duration listed on the ritual scroll. Local chapters also have the discretion to generate a unique plot effect or encounter based on a ritual gone awry that may not be specified on the ritual scroll.
        \n\n<b>Unwillng Targets:</b>
        \nSometimes rituals are cast on unwilling recipients. The player of an unwilling recipient may inform the ritual marshal that he or she wishes her character to resurrect rather than accept the ritual. In the case of ritual effects delivered outside the context of a ritual casting, the player may choose to have their character immediately dissipate and head to the nearest earth circle for resurrection, following the normal rules.
        \nIn such cases, the casting still continues for its proper duration and then the ritual marshal checks for failures normally. Any failures that could have a detrimental effect on the recipient of the ritual are ignored, and the failures affect the caster or others in the Circle normally.  A recipient of a ritual cannot choose to die in order to avoid the affects of an Obliteration, Banish to Other Plane, or Divestiture.
        \nRemember that a caster cannot waylay, cast spells upon, or otherwise restrain a person inside the Circle of Power once the ritual casting begins.
    </string>

    <!-- After Casting Strings -->

    <string name="after_casting"><b>Clean-up:</b>
        \nOnce success or failure has been resolved, the ritual marshal should collect all ritual components and ritual scrolls consumed in the rituals. These will be turned into the Logistics staff to be registered in the campaign’s database. If there are more components in the caster’s possession than were needed to cast the ritual, the caster may designate which components were consumed as long as they meet the requirements set forth in the ritual scroll.</string>

    <!-- Ritual Manipulations Strings -->

    <string name="rit_manip_title"><b>Ritual Manipulations</b></string>
    <string name="rit_manip_casters_mark"><b>Caster\'s Mark</b>
        \n\nThis allows the caster to add a small sigil or rune on the target of the ritual. This can be no larger than 3" on a side. This Mark will remain as long as the ritual with this ability remains on the item, and cannot be removed from the item while any rituals of this batch remain.
        \nThis ability may only be taken once. Plot must approve the design of the sigil to be placed on the Item.
        \nThe caster must have five levels of Formal Magic from the appropriate school above the difficulty of the ritual to be cast.</string>
    <string name="rit_manip_improved_chance"><b>Improved Chance</b>
        \n\nThis will add 1% success chance to the ritual being cast. This ability can only be used five times per ritual and never for a greater chance than 95%.
        \n\nThis is accomplished by rolling either two ten-sided die (with one representing the “ten” column and one representing the “ones” column) or rolling one die twice – first for the tens digit then again for the ones digit.
        \n\nThe caster must have five levels of Formal Magic from the appropriate school above the difficulty of the ritual to be cast.
    </string>
    <string name="rit_manip_insert_component"><b>Insert Component</b>
        \n\nThis allows the caster to substitute one component for a different one listed on the Ritual scroll. The caster needs to have at least one each of the components listed on the scroll; this allows for “additional reagents” for higher casting.
        \n\nThe caster must have five levels of Formal Magic from the appropriate school above the difficulty of the ritual to be cast.
    </string>
    <string name="rit_manip_lore_answer"><b>Lore Answer</b>
        \n\nThis ability allows the caster to enter a note on the magic item tag which dictates what information, if any, the caster of a Lore ritual will receive.
        \n\nFor each purchase of this ability, the caster may stipulate one “answer” which will be the first answer the caster of the Lore Ritual will receive from Plot. It is up to the discretion of Plot how much, if anything, the caster of the Lore ritual will receive beyond this answer.
        \n\nThe caster must have five levels of Formal Magic from the appropriate school above the difficulty of the ritual to be cast.
    </string>
    <string name="rit_manip_second_chance"><b>Second Chance</b>
        \n\nThis allows the caster to make a second die roll if the first fails. For every purchase of this manipulation, the caster gains a 10% chance to avoid failing the ritual (up to a maximum of 50%).
        \n\nThis can only be used once per ritual. Points for this must be allocated prior to casting the ritual.
        \n\nThe caster must have five levels of Formal Magic from the appropriate school above the difficulty of the ritual to be cast.
    </string>
    <string name="rit_manip_conservative_casting"><b>Conservative Casting</b>
        \n\nThis allows the use of one less component. This ability cannot be combined with any other skill that allows a reduction in component cost and may only be purchased once.
        \n\nAll components as specified on the scroll must be present at the time of casting. After the ritual has been successfully cast, the caster may choose and retain the component(s) which were not consumed due to this Ritual Manipulation.
        \n\n<i>For example: Belethevis wants to cast a Spirit Link which requires 4 reagents: a Truesilver, a Wand, a Penna, and a Heartstone. He uses a point of High Magic for Ritual Manipulation: Conservative Casting on the ritual. When he casts it, he has all four reagents as specified on the scroll to begin the casting. Once the ritual is complete, he decides to not have the Heartstone consumed.</i>
        \n\nThe caster must have ten levels of Formal Magic from the appropriate school above the difficulty of the ritual to be cast.
    </string>
    <string name="rit_manip_disguised_casting"><b>Disguised Casting</b>
        \n\nThis ability renders a ritual so that observers and creatures in the area are not informed they “feel magic all around them” thus preventing the magical emanations which would alert creatures to the presence of the ritual caster. In addition, anyone studying the ritual is unable to determine if the ritual is Earth, Celestial or Necromantic in nature.
        \n\nThe caster must have ten levels of Formal Magic from the appropriate school above the difficulty of the ritual to be cast.
    </string>
    <string name="rit_manip_quicken_casting"><b>Quicken Casting</b>
        \n\nThis will reduce casting time by 20% with a maximum time reduction of 80% (with four purchases). The target of this ritual may refuse to allow the time reduction to work. This ability will not work with any ritual which is listed as “unavoidable” such as Obliterate, Divestiture, or Banish to Other Plane.
        \n\nThe caster must have ten levels of Formal Magic from the appropriate school above the difficulty of the ritual to be cast
    </string>
    <string name="rit_manip_spark_of_empowerment"><b>Spark of Empowerment</b>
        \n\nWith this, a caster can “supercharge” the ritual they are casting, granting a greater effect for twenty-four hours or until the next Logistics Period, whichever is shorter. This cannot be extended by any means. After this period, these items return to their base ritual stats as the magic settles down.
        \n\nThe exact nature of how a ritual is more effective is up to the local Plot team. The more impressive role-playing and ritual casting performed, the greater the Empowerments.
        \n\nThis ability cannot be stacked with other Empowerment abilities.
        \n\nThe caster must have ten levels of Formal Magic from the appropriate school above the difficulty of the ritual to be cast.
    </string>
    <string name="rit_manip_choose_flaw"><b>Choose Flaw</b>
        \n\nThe caster may choose to add a flaw to the item from one of the following flaws. The caster may purchase this manipulation multiple times to add more flaws on items.
        \n\n• Limit the item’s use to a specific race or prohibit a specific race from using this item
        \n• Require a specific Build Skill to use or requiring the user not have a specific Build Skill
        \n• Require a certain action, phrase or gesture before, during or after activating
        \n• Require the item be worn or held or manipulated in a certain way
        \n• The item will only function under specific conditions (such as time of day or in specific weather)
        \n• The bearer of the item takes half damage from &lt;stone, lightning, ice, or flame&gt; while taking double damage from &lt;stone, lightning, ice, or flame&gt;. (Note: this can never affect healing).
        \n\nIf contradictory flaws exist, the item is rendered unusable. Flaws are applied to an item, not to specific rituals. Thus, so long as an item retains any rituals (and thus a Magic Item tag), all flaws on that item remain.
        \n\nThe caster must have fifteen levels of Formal Magic from the appropriate school above the difficulty of the ritual to be cast.
        \n\nNote: Flaws do not apply if a player does not know about them, however, any communication about the item’s powers (such as Identification or handing an item off from one person to another) must include an OOG communication detailing the flaws.
        \n\n<i>For example: Terin picks up an unidentified item. He doesn’t know the flaws or benefits yet. Later he goes and gets it Identified. At this time, he’s given the tag and the flaw is told to him (“You take double damage from Flame”). Terin then sells the item to Ena, telling Ena only about the benefits in-game (“Look, this does a Purify twice a day!”), but when he hands over the tag he also is required to tell Ena OOG about the flaw.</i>
        \n\nThe intent of this clarification is that players with knowledge of any powers of the item should also (even if only OOG) be informed of the flaws of the item.
    </string>
    <string name="rit_manip_obvious_power"><b>Obvious Power</b>
        \n\n This allows the caster to create an item which has a flaw added to it where anyone who inspects the item is able to identify the Aspect of the magic (Earth, Celestial or Necromantic) without the need for a Greater Celestial Circle of Power or a Lore ritual.
        \n\nIf an Obfuscate ritual exists on an item or is added to the item at any later time while this ritual is still active, this ability will be removed.
        \n\nThe caster must have fifteen levels of Formal Magic from the appropriate school above the difficulty of the ritual to be cast
    </string>
    <string name="rit_manip_terminate_ritual"><b>Terminate Ritual</b>
        \n\nThis ability allows the caster to voluntarily end the ritual casting with no ill effects. At any time during the ritual, the caster may activate the ability, ending the casting and retaining possession of all the ritual components and scrolls as if the ritual had not been started.
        \n\nThe caster must have twenty levels of Formal Magic from the appropriate school above the difficulty of the ritual to be cast
    </string>
    <string name="rit_manip_touch_of_empowerment"><b>Touch of Empowerment</b>
        \n\nThis allows the caster to “supercharge” the ritual they are casting, granting a greater effect for a maximum of five days, which cannot be extended by any means. After the five day duration, these items return to their base ritual stats as the magic settles down.
        \n\nThe exact nature of how a ritual is more effective is up to the local Plot team. The more impressive role-playing and ritual casting performed, the greater the Empowerments.
        \n\nThis ability cannot be stacked with other Empowerment abilities.
        \n\nThe caster must have twenty levels of Formal Magic from the appropriate school above the difficulty of the ritual to be cast.
    </string>
    <string name="rit_manip_true_conservation"><b>True Conservation</b>
        \n\nThis allows the caster to use two less components. All components as specified on the scroll must be present at the time of casting. After the ritual has been successfully cast, the caster may choose and retain the component(s) which were not consumed due to this Ritual Manipulation.
        \n\n<i>For example: Belthivis wants to cast a Spirit Link which requires four reagents: a Truesilver, a Wand, a Penna, and a Heartstone. He uses a point of High Magic for Ritual Manipulation: Conservative Casting on the ritual.
        \n\nWhen he casts it, he must have all four reagents as specified on the scroll to begin the casting (as per the rulebook). However, after he successfully casts it, he can pick one reagent of his choice which is not consumed in the casting.</i>
        \n\nThis can only be purchased once and cannot be combined with any other skill that allows a reduction in component cost.
        \n\nThe caster must have twenty-five levels of Formal Magic from the appropriate school above the difficulty of the ritual to be cast.
    </string>
    <string name="rit_manip_alternate_component"><b>Alternate Component</b>
        \n\nThe caster may add one additional “base component” to the scroll, allowing them to gather resources easier.
        \n\n<i>For example, Belthivis has a scroll requiring three components: Wand, Pyrotis and Jetsam. With this skill, he can now add Feyander to the list. He needs twenty-four components total for the ritual, so now he can mix and match from these four reagents as long as there is at least one each of the Wand, Pyrotis and Jetsam listed on the scroll.</i>
        \n\nThe caster must have thirty levels of Formal Magic from the appropriate school above the difficulty of the ritual to be cast.
    </string>
    <string name="rit_manip_true_empowerment"><b>True Empowerment</b>
        \n\nThis allows the caster to “supercharge” the ritual they are casting, granting a greater effect for a maximum of five days, which cannot be extended by any means.
        \n\nAfter the five day duration, these items return to their base ritual stats as the magic settles down.
        \n\nThe exact nature of how a ritual is more effective is up to the local Plot team. The more impressive role-playing and ritual casting performed, the greater the Empowerments.
        \n\nDifferent kinds of Empowerments cannot stack on an item. Only one type of Empowerment (Spark of Empowerment, Touch of Empowerment or True Empowerment) can be on any one item at a time. Also, only one Empowerment of the same type can be on one item at a time.
        \n\nIf a flaw duplicates a ritual effect (such as Cloak, Bane, per day or times ever, etc.) it must be counted against the twenty ritual limit of an item. Flaws which do not duplicate ritual effects will not count against the twenty ritual limit of an item.
        \n\nUnlike other Empowerment abilities, when a True Empowered ritual fades back to normal, it will leave behind a beneficial Flaw on the item subject to the discretion of the Plot Committee.
        \n\nThis Flaw will remain with the ritual for its entire duration and is not subject to the five day expiration.
        \n\nThe caster must have thirty-five levels of Formal Magic from the appropriate school above the difficulty of the ritual to be cast
    </string>
    <string name="rit_manip_casting_insight"><b>Casting Insight</b>
        \n\nThis ability allows the caster to roll twice to determine the success chance of their ritual. The caster can then choose whichever die roll result they prefer of the two. These results are taken before any other Manipulations or High Magic abilities are used.
        \n\nThis ability may only be purchased once per ritual.
        \n\nThe caster must have forty levels of Formal Magic from the appropriate school above the difficulty of the ritual to be cast.
    </string>

    <!-- Placeholder String -->

<!--
    <string name="rit_manip_improved_chance"><b></b>
        \n\n
    </string>
-->

</resources>
